Guide to the Annette Weiner Papers MC 152
New York University Archives
Annette Weiner Papers
1933-1997
1970-1997
New York University Archives
Weiner, Annette B., 1933-
MC 152
81 Linear Feet in 142 boxes
Annette B. Weiner was a prominent anthropologist and Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Science at New York Universitiy from 1991-1996. The materials contained in this collection include administrative memoranda, correspondence, reports, publications, newspaper clippings and papers produced during three distinct phases of Dr. Weiner's career. The earliest material was generated during her years as a graduate student involved in anthropological fieldwork. Another portion comes from her early academic career at the University of Texas. She continued her anthropological work as Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Science at NYU.
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In December of 1997, 49 boxes of material were donated to the New York University Archives by Dr. Weiner's husband, Dr. William E. Mitchell, emeritus professor of anthropology at the University of Vermont. Recommendations for grants, books and articles; letters of recommendation; and student grades and similar confidential records have been removed from the collection at the donor's request. The accession number associated with this collection is 99.002.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading, then chronologically within each subject/author heading in nine series:
I. Correspondence
II. Course Materials
III. Field notes
IV. Article Reprints
V. Conferences
VI. Publications and Related Material
VI. Bryn Mawr College Materials
VIII. Professional Organizations
IX. Dissertations
Biographical Note
Dr. Annette Barbara Cohen Weiner (1933-1997) was born in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. In 1968 she received her B.A. from the University of Pennsylvania and in 1974 her doctorate from Bryn Mawr College. She was best known for her work challenging the pioneering studies of cultural anthropologist Bronislaw Malinowski conducted in the 1930s and 1940s with indigenous people living on the Trobriand Islands of Papua, New Guinea. Malinowski published several volumes that are considered classics in the field of anthropology. Dr. Weiner revisited Malinowski's findings by further articulating the roles played by women in Trobriand society. In 1976 the University of Texas published her doctoral thesis as Women of Value, Men of Renown: New Perspectives in Trobriand Exchange. She subsequently published La richesse des femmes ou comment l'esprit vient aux homes (Iles Trobriand), a French translation of her doctoral thesis (1983); The Trobrianders of Papua New Guinea (1988); Cloth and Human Experience (1989) and Inalienable Possessions: The Paradox of Keeping-While-Giving (1992). Additional published works include encyclopedic entries, reviews and numerous articles for anthropological journals such as American Anthropologist, American Ethnologist and Pacific Studies.
The recipient of numerous research grants and fellowships, Dr. Weiner conducted most of her ethnographic fieldwork from 1969-1991 in diverse regions that included Western Samoa; Bastrop County, Texas; Sind, Pakistan; Antigua; and Guatemala. She also served as a consultant for the film Trobriand Islanders of Papua New Guinea (1988), part of the Disappearing World Series produced for Granada Television in England. In 1991 she received the Grand Prix award for the film from the Bilan du Film Ethnographique, Paris, France.
Dr. Weiner began her academic career in 1973-74 as a visiting Assistant Professor at Franklin and Marshall College. In 1974 she was appointed Assistant Professor at the University of Texas and by 1980 was promoted to the position of Associate Professor of Anthropology. She came to New York University as a professor of anthropology in 1981 and in 1984 was appointed as the Kriser Distinguished Professor of Anthropology, a title she maintained until the time of her death. Beginning in 1982 she also served as the Chair of the Department of Anthropology. Her responsibilities included the recruitment of full-time faculty, the revision of existing undergraduate and graduate programs, and the development of new programs in physical anthropology, archaeology, linguistics and fundraising. She was also responsible for organizing major conferences and symposia in the U.S., France, Italy, Austria, Australia and the USSR. Dr. Weiner resigned as the Dean of GSAS in 1996 as a result of illness.
Dr. Weiner held offices at the Society for Cultural Anthropology, the American Anthropological Association, the American Ethnological Society and the Association of Social Anthropology in Oceania. She also worked as a consultant on several executive and editorial boards such as the Social Science Council (1993), the Encyclopedia of Cultural Anthropology (1993), Encyclopedia Americana (1993) and the Smithsonian Series in Ethnographic Inquiry (1985).
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The contents of this collection include material generated by Dr. Annette Weiner between 1960-1997 representing her academic career and service to New York University. The papers document her years as a student, field-work in Paupa New Guinea and include numerous reprinted articles that reflect Dr. Weiner's work and interests. Administrative records mark her tenure as Dean of New York University Graduate School of Arts and Sciences (1991-1996).
Materials in the collection include correspondence, field notebooks, and published and unpublished writings (reviews, course materials and dissertations).
The dates assigned to some folders containing copies of articles and letters refer to the dates of the original documents, not the dates of the copies.
Anthropology -- Research.; Correspondence.; Field notes.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Photographs.; Yearbooks.; Scrapbooks.; Ethnology.; Papua New Guinea.; Dissertations.; Articles.; Women -- Papua New Guinea -- Trobriand Islands; Ethnology -- Papua New Guinea -- Trobriand Islands; Economic anthropology -- Oceania -- Methodology; Trobriand Islands (Papua New Guinea) -- Social life and customs; Ethnology -- Melanesia; Women -- Oceania -- Social conditions; Political anthropology -- Melanesia; New York University; Beidelman, T.O. (Thomas O.), 1931-; American Anthropological Association; Malinowski, Bronislaw, 1884-1942; Freeman, Derek; Cain, Horst; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Bryn Mawr College; Myers, Fred R., 1948-; Mitchell, William E.; Meleisea, Penelope Schoeffel; Society for Cultural Anthropology (U.S.); Wormsley, William Edward; New York University. Department of Anthropology; New York University. Graduate School of Arts and Science; Senft, Gunter, 1952-; Weiner, Annette B., 1933-
- Series I: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence between Annette Weiner and various colleagues.
  - Adam, Keith, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code: 3 1142 0405 7801 8
  - Adams, John, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Rick, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Affleck, Don, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Appadurai, Arjun, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arens, William, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arno, Andrew, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arth, Malcolm, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Asch, Timothy, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ashworth, Kenneth H., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Atkinson, Jane Monnig, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Avei, Moi, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Babcock, Barbara A., 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barraud, Cecile, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Basso, Keith, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bataille, Marie Claire, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Battaglia Jones, Debbora, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Beidelman, Thomas O., 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beier, Ulli, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bell, Ingrid, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Berlowitz, Leslie, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Berde, Stuart, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Betre, Monica, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Blanchard, Kendall A., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Block, M., undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Blu, Carren I., 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bourdieu, Pierre, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brady, Ivan, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Brademas, John, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Brennan, Mary Ursula, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brett-Smith, Sarah Catharine, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brown, Michael F., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brown, Susan Douchen, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Buuster, Ximeue, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Burguiere, Andre, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Burke, Helena, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Caille, Alain, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Cain, Horst, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Campbell, Lawrence F., 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cassel, Joan, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Catlett, Stephen, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Chalfen, Richard, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Chawning, Ann, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Christine, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Clifford, James, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Counihan, Carole M., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Coville, Elizabeth, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Damon, Fred, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Davis, Natalie, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - d'Azevedo, Warren L., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - deBurlo, Charles R., 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Decopper, Daniel, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Heusch, Lucde, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - de Laguna, Frederica, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Delporte, Henri, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Dent Publishers, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Depew, Robert C., 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Deshen, Shlomo, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Di Cori, Paola, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Dumont, Louis, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Dwyer, Daisy Hilse, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Earle, Timothy, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Ebihara, May, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Edwards, Gregory, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Eggloff, Brian J., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Eickelman, Dale F., 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Emory University, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Etienne, Mona, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Feil, Daryl Keith, 1979-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 0405 7802 6
  - Fernandez, ..., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fernea, B.J., undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Firth, Raymond, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fisher, Helen, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Flowers, Betty S., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fortes, Meyer, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fortune, Reo, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Franklin, Sarah, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Freeman, Derek, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Furbee-Losee, Louanna, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gable, Eric, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gautier, Helene, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Geertz, Clifford, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gell, Alfred, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ginger, Ferrer, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ginsberg, Faye, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Glowczewski, Barbara, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Goddard, J.T., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Godelier, Maurice, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Goldstein, Judith, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Goodale, Jane, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Goodman, Lawrence B., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Greenstadt, William M., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gregory, Chris, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Guiart, ..., 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Guidieri, Remo, 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Guksch, Christian E., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Hamilton, Anne, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Hammond, Joyce, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hancock, W. (xerox of 1918 letter), undated, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 30A)
  - Handelman, Don, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Harris, Alfred, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hartman, Joan E., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Harvard College, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Harvard University, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Heider, Karl G., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Heller, ..., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hooper, Antony, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hrdy, Sarah Blaffer, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Huntsman, Judith, 1970-1983 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hutchins, Edwin, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Ichioka, Yasuko, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Iteanu, Andre, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Jackman, Harry, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Jones, Colin H., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Jones, Philip, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Kahn, Mimi, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Kapferrer, Bruce, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Kaprow, Miriam Lee, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Keane, Webb, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Keeler, Ward, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Keely, Ann, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Keesing, Roger M., 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Kelly, Judy, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Kennedy, Jean, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Kenyon, Sue, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Kerapa, Ralph, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Kilborne, Benjamin, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Kirk, Malcolm, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Knei-Paz, B., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Kriser, David B., 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Langness, L.L., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Larcom, Joan, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Leach, Edmund, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Leach, Jerry W., 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Leacock, Eleanor, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Lee, Richard, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Lenz, Ilse, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Lewis, Joan, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Lidoff, Joan, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Lieber, Mike, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Linderbaum, Shirley, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Logan, Kathleen S., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Lomax, Alan, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Luig, Ute, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Lutkehaus, Nancy, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Lynch, Owen, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - MacCormack, Carol, 1974-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 0405 7803 4
  - MacDougal, David, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - MacIntyre, Martha, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - MacLeod, M.D., 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Manning, Frank, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Marcus, George, 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Margolin, Frederique, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Martin, Emily, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mattingly, Paul H., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - McDevitt, Thomas, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - McKinnen, ..., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Meggitt, Mervyn, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Melasea, Penny, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Mersch, Matthias, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Metraux, Rhoda, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Middleton, John, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mintz, Jerome, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mintz, Sydney W., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Australia, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Montague, Susan, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mosuwadoga, Geoffrey, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Munn, Nancy, 1974-1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Myers, Fred, 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Nader, Laura, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Napier, David, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Nardi, Bonnie, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - National Geographic, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Needham, Rodney, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Nisbett, Alec, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Noel, John, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Norick, Frank, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - O'Donnell, Doris, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - O'Flaherty, Ed, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - O'Neal, Russell, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Osmundsen, Lita, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Parmetier, Ricjard J., 1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Peterson, Nic, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Pfeiffer, John, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Philippakis, Renee Hirschon, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Pitt-Rivers, Julian, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Poole, Fitz John Potter, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Powell, Harry, 1972-1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Price, Richard, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Prince, Carl, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Rappaport, R.A., 1978-1986 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Reina, R., 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Renne, Elishe, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Ritchie, Jim, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Ronis, Max L., 1984 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Rensberger, Boyce, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Rouch, Jean, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Rubinstein, Bob, 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Ruby, Jay, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Sahlins, Marshall, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 0405 7804 2
  - Sanday, Peggy R., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1A)
  - Sapir, J. David, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scheffler, Harold, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Schieffler, Back, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Schneider, David, 1973-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Schoeffel, Penny, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Schwartz, Albert, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Scodetti, G., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Selby, Henry, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Senft, Gunter, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sexton, Lorraine, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Shack, William, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Shapiro, Judith, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Shokeid, Moshe, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Shore, Bradd, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Silverman, Martin, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Skalnik, Peter, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Smith, Heidi, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Wendy, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Stocking, George W., 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Stoler, Paul, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Stow, J. Randolph, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Strathern, Andrew, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Strathern, Marilyn, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Taureg, Martin, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Tcheakezoff, Serge, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tilly, Louise A., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Topolsky, Mary S., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Thmarkin, Daniel, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Turton, David, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Upton, Caroline J., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Valens, Lucette, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Van Dongan, Haus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Wagner, Roy, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Wallace, Anthony, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Wallyford School, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Wason, David, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Waterbury, Ron, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Wax, Murray L., 1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Wayne, Helene, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Weiner, Jim, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Weinstock, Steven, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - White, John, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - White, Peter, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Wiesner, Polly, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wikan, Unni, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Williams, Jason, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Williamson, Samuel J., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Wilnsen, S., 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Wilson, Peter J., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Yale University Library Archives, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Yamaguchi, Masao, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Yerkovich, Sally, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Young, Michael, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Correspondences on GSAS Dean Appointment, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 0405 7805 9
  - Letter and Request, 1986-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1A)
  - Accomando, Claire Hsu, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Richard Newbold, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Adler, Norman, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Aguiar, Neuma, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Peter, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Allen, W.B., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Anawalt, Patricia, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Anderson, Astrid, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Asad, Talal, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Atkins, Robert and Prakash Daswani, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Baba, Marietta L., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Barnes, Annie S., 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Barnet, Jane, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Barth, Frederik, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Beruch, Syvia, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Battaglia, Deborah, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Beck, Sam, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18A)
  - Beeman, William, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Bennet, Linda, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Benthall, Jonathan C., 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Bestor, Ted, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Blanchard, Kendall, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Borofsky, Rob, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Bowles, Ian, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Brademas, John, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Brenneis, Don, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Browner, Carol, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Bruner, Edward, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Buchholz, Ted, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Buikstra, Jane, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Burke, Ariane, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Bush, George, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Caille, Alain, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Canadian Museum of Civilisation, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Carlson, Robert G., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Chavez, Leo, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Cheal, David, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Clark, Desmond, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Clark, Bridget J., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Cohen, Jeffrey, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Cohn, Jan, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Colen, Shellee, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Collier, George A., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Coombe, Rosemary J., 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Cooper, Joseph, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Cornman, Jack, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Costa, Lee Ray, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Costello, Julia G., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Counts, Dorothy, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Crain, Jay B., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Custer, Rick, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - De Coppet, Daniel, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - De Laguna, Frederica, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Dennis, Carolyn, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Deshen, Shlomo, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Dickemann, Mildred, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Dixon, Dan, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Donner, Bill, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Edwards, Allma Kora, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Ehrhardt, Kathleen L., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Ellison, Peter T., 1995 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Elliston, Deborah A., 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Ember, Melvin, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Estroff, Sue E., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Featherman, David L., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Feil, D., 1990 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Fernandes, Sousa, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Fernea, Robert, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Foster, Robert, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Franklin, Sarah, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Freeman, Derek, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Friedan, Betty, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Furbee, Louanna, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Gabrielle, ..., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Gallaher, Art, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Gates, Louis Henry Jr., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Geirnaert, Danielle, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Gewert, Deborah, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Geyer, Helen, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Gibbons, Ann, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Godelier, Maurice, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Goldschmidt, Walter, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Golla, Victor, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Green, Sheila M., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 85)